The law has limits. He does not.
Jack Reacher is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
One morning in an ordinary town, five people are shot
dead in a seemingly random attack.
All evidence points to a single suspect: an ex-military
sniper who is quickly brought into custody.
The interrogation yields one written note: 'Get Jack Reacher!'.
Reacher, an enigmatic ex-Army investigator, believes the authorities have the
right man but agrees to help the sniper's defense attorney.
However, the more Reacher delves into the case, the less clear-cut it appears.
So begins an extraordinary chase for the truth, pitting Jack Reacher against an
unexpected enemy, with a skill for violence and a secret to keep.
Jack Reacher, played by Tom Cruise.
Helen Rodin, played by Rosamund Pike.
D.A. Alex Rodin, played by Richard Jenkins.
Det. Emerson, played by David Oyelowo.
Zec Chelovek, played by Werner Herzog.
Charlie, played by Jai Courtney.
Jack Reacher is a 2012 American action thriller film written and directed by Christopher
McQuarrie, starring Tom Cruise and based on Lee Child's novel One Shot.
Cruise portrays the title character and the supporting cast features Rosamund Pike, Werner
Herzog, Robert Duvall, David Oyelowo, Richard Jenkins, and Jai Courtney.
The film focuses on a normally non-contactable former US Army Major MP investigator Jack Reacher, who is called upon to aid in
a homicide investigation involving a trained military sniper believed to be responsible for a mass shooting.
The film entered production in October 2011, and was completed in January 2012.
It was filmed entirely on location in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
The musical score was composed by Joe Kraemer and
performed by the Hollywood Studio Symphony.
The film's premiere screening in Pittsburgh was postponed after the Sandy Hook Elementary School shooting; the movie was released in North
America one week later on December 21, 2012, where it received generally positive reviews and was successful at the box office.
A sequel was developed with Cruise, titled Jack Reacher: Never Go Back, based on the
2013 novel Never Go Back, which was released on October 21, 2016.
The film explores themes of sniper, coma, based on
novel or book, detective, investigation.
The tone is emotional and intense.